Finding Aid for the Lawrence Clark Powell Papers LSC.0229
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Various Publications and Manuscripts
  - Land of Fiction (), 1951
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Land of Fiction; Thirty-two novels and stories about Southern California from Ramona to The Loved One: A bibliographical essay. Los Angeles: Glen Dawson, 1952.; (Typescript, [48] leaves) (Box 24, Folder 1)
      With holograph corrections including one page proof with printing instructions.
    - Land of Fiction..., ([66]pp.) (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and notes, 1954. (Box 24, Folder 3)
      re the acquisition of the 32 titles of Land of Fiction for exhibition purposes.
    - Land of Fiction... In California Librarian, June 1953. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Land of Fiction; Thirty-two novels and stories about Southern California from Ramona to The Loved One: A bibliographical essay. Los Angeles: Glen Dawson, 1952.; ([66]pp., 2 copies) (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Introduction of Gerhard Muench (), 1953
    - Introduction of Gerhard Muench by Lawrence Clark Powell and Program of Gerhard Muench's Concert, July 15, 1953.; (Typescript, 1 leaf. Program, 1 leaf) (Box 24, Folder 1)
      (Tapes in Box 81)
  - Introduction of Panel on Branch Libraries (), 1953
    - Introduction of Panal on Branch Libraries by LCP. ACRL meeting, 1953.; (3 leaves typescript carbon copy) (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Books Determine (), 1954
    - An address given at the Fifteenth Biennial Conference of the Southwestern Library Association. Albuquerque, November 4, 1954.; (Ditto typescript, 11 leaves) (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - In Papers and Proceedings of the Southwestern Library Association. Fifteenth Biennial Conference, Alburquerque, New Mexico., November 3-5, 1954. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Wilson Library Bulletin, September 1955. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Libraries in the Southwest (), 1955
    Libraries of the Southwest - Entire File to be Used Only With the Written Permission of Lawrence Clark Powell (October 1970).
    See box 81 for tapes of the conference.
    - Correspondence, preliminary drafts, etc. planning for Conference on Libraries in the Southwest, 1953-1954. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, drafts and typescript copies of Conference participants' presentations, etc., January-April 1955. (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, typescripts, etc., May 1955-. (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Patricia Peylore's file on the Conference. (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Publications After the Conference:
      - Mexico Challenges the Future Joint meeting of the Southwest Conference and the California Library Association, Southern District. Occidental College [Program]., April 15 and 16, 1955. (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - Reynolds, J.E. Low Barometer in the Southwest. Reprinted from Library Journal, October 1, 1955.; (3pp.) (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Libraries in the Southwest. In UCLA Occasional Papers (no.3). Reissued, 1961.; (45pp.) (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Libraries In The Southwest. Their Growth - Strengths - Needs. In UCLA Occasional Papers (no.3)., 1955.; (70pp.) (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Esther Colville Waldron (), 1956
    - [Death of Esther Waldron], []., 1956; (Holograph manuscript, 6 leaves) (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - City College Librarian Dies; Sleep pills Blamed. In Los Angeles Times., April 12, 1956. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Henry R. Wagner and his work (), 1957
    - Henry R. Wagner and His Work. Eulogy given at the Services held by the Zamorano Club. Forest Lawn, April 1957.; (Ditto typescript, 6 leaves) (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - His Work. In: Memoriam, Tributes paid at the Bier of Henry Raup Wagner, April 1957. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Henry R. Wagner, 1862-1957. Antiquarian Bookman, May 13, 1957. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - The Malibu (), 1958
    - Letters to and from Lawrence Clark Powell, 1957-19??. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - The Malibu by W.W. Robinson and Lawrence Clark Powell. Los Angeles: Dawson's Bookshop, 1958. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - The Battle for Malibu. Broadcast no.3874 - U.E. Sunday, Columbia Broadcasting System, KNX, Los Angeles, 9:30 A.M.; KCBS, San Francisco, 9:15 A.M., 1693. May 31, 1959.; (4pp. mimeographed) (Box 25, Folder 3)
      University Explorer script based on The Malibu by W.W. Robinson and Lawrence Clark Powell.
    - Paul Horgan. Wall of Flame. The Saturday Evening Post (vol.232, no.5)., August 1, 1959. (Box 25, Folder 4)
      A story based on the experience of Dr. and Mrs. Lawrence Clark Powell.
    - The Malibu, then and now, 1957-1961. (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Correspondence, clippings, publicity, etc. re publication.
    - The Malibu, Southern California's famous rancho; its romantic history and present charm. Los Angeles: Ward Ritchie Press, 1970. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - A Southwestern Century (), 1958
    - Letters to Lawrence Clark Powell from various persons, 1958-19??. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous--publication announcement and review. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - A Southwestern Century, A bibliography of one hundred books of non-fiction about the Southwest. Chosen and annotated by Lawrence Clark Powell. Illustration by Tom Lea. Van Nuys, California: J.E. Reynolds, Bookseller, 1958. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - A Southwestern Century, a catalog of books new and out-of-print, based on the sparkling new bibliography by Dr. Lawrence Clark Powell, Librarian, UCLA. In International Bookfinders List (no.92). Beverly Hills, []., 1958 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Thomas S. Dabagh (), 1959
    - [Death of Thomas S. Dabagh], [1959].; (Holograph manuscript, 5 leaves) (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - [Thomas S. Dabagh]. From the Librarian, UCLA Librarian (vol.12, no.9), February 6, 1959. (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Book Reviews
  - KFAC
    - Books I Like; a series of talks over radio station KFAC, Los Angeles, March 19-May 14, 1935.; (63 leaves, typescript) (Box 26, Folder 1)
      These talks were sponsored by Jacob Zeitlin's Bookshop.
  - Westways, December 1944-August 1950; (52 articles)
    I Want A Book to Read and Of Western Books and Writers; a series of articles by Lawrence Clark Powell appearing in Westways (monthly magazine of the Automobile Club of Southern California).
    [With some ommissions]
    Original typescript drafts as submitted to Phil Townsend Hanna, the editor.
    (see below)
    - I Want a Book to Read. []., December 1944-November 1945 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Of Western Books and Writers, [], v.d.
      - []., February-December 1946 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - []., January-December 1947 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - []., January-December 1948 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - []., March-December 1949 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - []., January October 1950 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Letters to and from Lawrence Clark Powell, 1948-1949. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Cavalcade of Books
    - [Book reviews on Cavalcade of Books, ]., December 26, 1954; (2pp.) (Box 26, Folder 9)
- Bibliographies of Lawrence Clark Powell Publications
  - 1932-1949
    - Lawrence Clark Powell; a Selective Bibliography of his Published Writings, 1932-1949., (Negative Photostat, 3 leaves) (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Lawrence Clark Powell; a Bibliography of his Published Writings, 1938-1949., (Negative Photostat, 5 leaves) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - 1932-1953
    - Heron, David Winston. Lawrence Clark Powell; a Selective Bibliography of His Published Writings, 1932-1953., (Ditto typescript, 8 leaves) (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Books and printing, a selected list of periodicals, 1800-1942. New York, (Reviewed by LCP, )., 1943. 1944 (Box 26, Folder 1a)
    - Heron, David Winston. Lawrence Clark Powell; a Bibliography of his Published Writings, 1932-1953., (Ditto typescript, 8 leaves) (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Archer, H. Richard. Publications of Lawrence Clark Powell, June 1952-1953., (Photocopy, 1 leaf) (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - 1954-1955
    - Lyon, Ralph, Jr. Publications of Lawrence Clark Powell, July 1, 1953-June 30, 1954., (Typescript, 1 leaf) (Box 26, Folder 6)
      Also includes a memo from Ralph Lyon, Jr. to Lawrence Clark Powell, July 6, 1954.
    - By Lawrence Clark Powell; Bibliography of Writing Received for Faculty File, Archives, Special Collections, January-December 1955., (Typescript, 2 leaves) (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - 1931-1961
    - Rosenberg, Betty, comp., (Ditto typescript. 18 leaves) (Box 26, Folder 8)
      A Check-list of the Published Writings 1931-1958 of Lawrence Clark Powell, University Librarian.
    - Hinchliff, William Emerson, comp. Which Entrance to Library Service? A Selective Bibliography and Notes on Certain Essays by Lawrence Clark Powell, University Librarian (1944-1961) and Dean of the School of Library Service, University of California, Los Angeles. Santa Barbara, 1962.; ([10]pp.) (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - 1929-1963
    - Rosenberg, Betty, and Lois Ann Zechnick, comp. A checklist of the published writings 1929-1963 of Lawrence Clark Powell, Dean, School of Library Service, University of California, Los Angeles., (Ditto typescript, 26 leaves) (Box 26, Folder 10)
      Compiled 1958 by Betty Rosenberg and extended by Lois Ann Zechnick, 1963.
  - 1919-1966
    - Rosenberg, Betty, comp. Checklist of the published writings of Lawrence Clark Powell from 1919-1966. Introduction by W.W. Robinson. Los Angeles: University of California, University Library, (46pp.)
      See Box 41, folder 7.
    - Checklist., 1966; (Notes and typescript) (Box 26, Folder 11)
- Various Correspondents, etc.
  (Includes some manuscripts and publications by persons other than Lawrence Clark Powell. In alphabetical order by the correspondent of author's name)
  - Algar, James N.
    - Letter from James N. Algar to Lawrence Clark Powell plus an enclosure, 1955. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Antiquarian Booksellers
    - Letter from Lawrence Clark Powell to the Members, August 15, 1950. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Allen, John Houghten
    - Letter from John Houghton Allen to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1962. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Bird, Remsen DuBois
    - Letters from Remsen DuBois Bird to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1946-, and n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Remsen DuBois Bird to various persons, 1949-. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Letters from Remsen DuBois Bird to various persons (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to Remsen DuBois Bird, 1945-. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Letters from various persons to Remsen DuBois Bird, 1953-1959, and n.d. (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Letters from various persons to various persons, 1953-1959. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Bird, Remsen DuBois. News Comments., ([4] leaves) (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Brown, Ralph A.
    - Letter from Ralph A. Brown to Lawrence Clark Powell, February 23, 1951. (Box 27, Folder 1)
      With an enclosure, Directions to the Binder and title page to James Leoni's Some Designs for Buildings Both Publick and Private. London: Printed by Thomas Edlin, 1726.
  - Crosby, Percy
    - Correspondence between Percy Crosby and Lawrence Clarl Powell, 1947-. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Dakin, Susanna (Mrs. Richard Y.)
    - Letter from Lawrence Clark Powell to Susanna Dakin, 1949. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Emblem, Donald
    - Letters from Donald Emblem and various persons to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1949-1957, and n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to Donald Emblem, 1949-1952. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts and publications by Donald Emblem. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Gardiner, Wrey
    - Correspondence between Wrey Gardiner and Lawrence Clark Powell, 1948-. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Greer, Scott
    - Letters from Scott Greer to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1945-1947, and n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to Scott Greer, 1945-1950. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Haines, Helen E.
    - Letters from Helen E. Haines to Lawrence Clark Powell, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Haines, Helen E. New Lamps for Old. In Occasional Papers (no.7), Pennsylvania Library Club., April 1899. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Braskin, Alice (Sister of Helen E. Haines). Written from a Little Room. In Pasadena Star-News News []., January 12, 1947-October 24, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Highet, Gilbert
    - The Springs of Clitmus. Los Angeles: Printed by W.M. Cheney for Lawrence Clark Powell, 1958. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - KPFK
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to various persons, 1959-. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Letters from various persons to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1959-, and n.d. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Laughlin, James
    - Letters from James Laughlin to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1948-1950. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to James Laughlin, 1946-1950. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - MacIntyre, C.F.
    - Letters from C.F. MacIntyre to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1959. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Storm, Theodore. October Lied, translated by C.F. MacIntyre. Los Angeles: The Ward Ritchie Press for friends of Fay and Lawrence Powell, 1945. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - MacLeish, Archibald
    - Letters from Archibald MacLeish to Lawrence Clark Powell,; an invitation honoring MacLeish at the 1943 UCLA Charter Day; a letter from the American Library Association to the U.S. Senate against the appointment of MacLeish as Librarian of Congress., 1941-1944 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Morgan, Elder R.
    - Correspondence between Elder R. Morgan and Lawrence Clark Powell, 1955-. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Parkinson, Thomas F.
    - Letters from Thomas F. Parkinson to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1949-. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to Thomas F. Parkinson, 1949-. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Patterson, Franklin
    - Letters from Franklin Patterson to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1943-1956. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to Franklin Patterson, 1949-1951. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Recommendations by Lawrence Clark Powell and personal and professional data of Franklin Patterson. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Powys, Llewelyn
    - A Catalogue of Llewelyn Powys Manuscripts in the possession of Miss Alyse Gregory with an accompanying letter from Alyse Gregory, 1953. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Pratley, Harry W.
    - Letter from Harry W. Pratley to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1960. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Richter, Conrad
    - Letters from Conrad Richter to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1953-1960. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to Conrad Richter, 1953-19??. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Rolle, Andrew F.
    - Letters from Andrew F. Rolle to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1950-1956, and n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to Andrew F. Rolle, 1950-1956. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to various persons., 1953-1956. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Letters to and from various persons including Andrew F. Rolle and Lawrence Clark Powell, 1941-1956 and n.d. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Typescripts and publications by Andrew F. Rolle. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Ross, Lillian Bos
    - Letters from Lillian B. Ross to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1949. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to Lillian B. Ross, 1949. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Ross, Robert E.
    - Letters from Robert E. Ross to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1956-19??. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to Robert E. Ross, 1956-19??. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Ryan, Don
    - Letters from Don Ryan to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1952-19??. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to Don Ryan, 1952-19??. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Letters from various persons to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1952-19??. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Schurch, Jack
    - Letters from Jack Schurch to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1931-. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Letter from Lawrence Clark Powell to Jack Schurch, February 4, 1957. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Sproul, Robert Gordon
    - Letters from Robert G. Sproul to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1952-. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Thompson, Lawrence S.
    - Faust: A Bicentennial Review by Lawrence S. Thompson, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Weeks, Edward
    - Letter from Lawrence Clark Powell to Edward Weeks, 1952. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - White, Carl M.
    - Letters from Carl M. White to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1954-1956. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to Carl M. White, 1954-1955. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Williams, Clinton
    - Letters from Clinton Williams to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1944-. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to Clinton Williams, 1950-. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
    - Letter from LCP to Special Collections, April 3, 1949. (Box 28, Folder 1)
- Lawrence Clark Powell Tape Recordings
  (Filed in alphabetical order by title)
  - Alchemy of Books--Review. Rexroth Reviews., July 26, 1954.; (3.75 IPS. 8-10 minutes) (Box 29 (A-L))
    Copied from reel 47B
  - Bibliographers of the Golden State. Zeitlen and verBrugge Lecture, UCLA, HB 1200, April 17, 1967.; (3.33 IPS) (Box 29)
  - Book selection. Univesity of Denver, Mary Roed Liberary, March 1961.; (3.75 IPS) (Box 29)
  - Building a great university library. University of Denver, Renaissance Room, March 1961.; (7.5 IPS. Full track Ampex) (Box 29)
  - Convocation address. Carleton College, Northfield, Minnesota. Introduction by Dr. Lawrence Gould, President of the college., February 26, 1961. (Box 29)
  - Convocation address. Macalester College, St. Paul, Minnesota., September 1962. (Box 29)
  - Down where the Rockies end. Address to PNLA-MPLA conference, Denver, Hilton Hotel., September 3, 1965.; (3.75 IPS) (Box 29)
  - Essences of Britain. Recorded, June 6, 1953.; (2 reels) (Box 29)
  - Great land of libraries. Keynote address, ALA, 84th annual conference, Detroit Michigan. Introduction by Edwin Castagna, president of the ALA., July 4, 1965.; (7.5 IPS. Full track. Copy no.2) (Box 29)
  - Home thoughts from abroad. UCSB, Campbell Hall., January 31, 1967.; (3.75 IPS) (Box 29)
  - Huxley memorial. UCLA, School of Library Service., February 27, 1964.; (Full track, 3.75 IPS) (Box 29)
  - Land of Fiction. Faculty lecture. (side 1) and Alchemy of Books. First version, to UCLA staff, before ALA meeting (side 2)., November 3, 1953; (3.75 IPS) (Box 29)
  - Language of the heart. Los Angeles City College., February 20, 1957.; (3.75 IPS) (Box 29)
  - Librarian as a bookman. (track 1) and Philosophy of library education. University of Denver, Mary Roed Library. (track 2)., March 1961; (3.75 IPS) (Box 30 (L-Z))
  - Larry Powell to Zamorano., January 8, 1958.; (3.75 IPS) (Box 30)
  - Magnetic field of books. Faculty Lectures series. Introduction by Dr. Andrew H. Horn., July 29, 1954.; (3.75 IPS) (Box 30)
  - New Mexico and the Southwest. Zamorano Club, Hodge-Banquet-University Club, Los Angeles., (2 reels. 3.75 IPS) (Box 30)
    Reminiscences by Frederick Webb Hodge with introduction and closing remarks by Ward Ritchie.
  - The Power to evoke. Address to the Manuscript Society, Columbus, Ohio. Recorded in Los Angeles, May 4, 1953. May 12, 1953. (Box 30)
  - Rivers and reading. Dedication, Los Angeles Beeghly Library, Juniata College. (side 1) and La Chanson de Roland (side 2)., October 11, 1963; (3.75 IPS) (Box 30)
  - Sky, Sun and Water. A discourse on the Southwest in honor of Frederick Webb Hodge on his 89th birthday. Zamorano Club, Los Angeles. Wednesday,, 6 o'clock., October 28, 1953; (Copy, 7.5 IPS) (Box 30)
  - Southern California Fiction Exhibit. On Todd Hunter's Ten O'clock Wire, KNX, 10:00 PM, June 11, 1953.; (3.75 IPS) (Box 30)
  - Summing up. Address to the CLA, April 16, 1966.; (3.75 IPS. .25 track) (Box 30)
  - This Dry and wrinkled land. Address delivered to Arizona State Library Association. At Tucson, Recorded at Los Angeles, April 11, 1953. April 14, 1953.; (3.75 IPS, original and 1 copy) (Box 30)
  - With the University Explorer. KHJ, Mutual Network., June 19, 1955.; (3.75 IPS) (Box 30)
    See Box 48, Tomorrow's History, for typescript.
    Listings continued in Box 81.
- Columbia Library School
  - Records
    - Year Book, A Record for One Year at Columbia University, 1954. (Box 31, Folder 1)
      [An Appointment and Memorandum Book for Lawrence Clark Powell]
    - Grade Book for Library Science 280 at Columbia University., (Blue Loose Leaf Binder) (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Suggested reading and lecture notes. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Assignments for Library Science 280
    - Preliminary Statement--Why I want to be a Librarian. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Library Leaders--Two Librarians. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports, A - L. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Annual Reports, M - Z. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence and notes. (Box 32, Folder 1)
      re Library Science 280--Theory of Administration.
    - Letters to Lawrence Clark Powell from the UCLA Library Staff, February-March 1954. (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Lawrence Clark Powell from the UCLA Library Staff, April-May 1954 and n.d. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Lawrence Clark Powell from various persons, 1954, and n.d. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Letters to and from various persons, 1954. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Lawrence Clark Powell from various persons, Spring 1954. (Box 32, Folder 6)
      re talks and articles.
- English 195--Libraries And Learning
  - Notes
    - Notes outlining the course--Libraries and Learning., (Holograph, [23] leaves) (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Grade Books and Exams, etc.
    - Spring 1956. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Spring 1957. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Spring 1958. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Spring 1959. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Manuscripts
    - Libraries and Learning. Syllabus & Bibliography for English 195., (Holograph, 14 leaves) (Box 33, Folder 6)
      Manuscript with corrections.
  - Correspondence
    - Letters to Lawrence Clark Powell from various persons, 1954-. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Publications
    - Libraries and Learning, Outlines and Bibliography for English 195. University of California, Los Angeles, v.d.
      - Spring Semester, 1956., (Mimeographed, 19 leaves) (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - UCLA Library Occasional Papers (no.5), 1956. (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - 1958. (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - 1959. (Box 33, Folder 11)
- California Library Association Records
  These records relate to Lawrence Clark Powell's participation in the activities of the Association, including his term as President, 1950.
  - Tickler File
    - Program. (Box 34)
    - State Capitol Program. (Box 34)
    - To be read at the opening General Session. (Box 34)
    - Business Meeting, June 22. (Box 34)
    - Executive Board Meeting, June 24. (Box 34)
    - Friday Night. (Box 34)
    - Mucicipal--Trustee Luncheon. (Box 34)
    - ALA Federal Relations Office. (Folder Folders A-D, Box 34)
    - Border District (Proposed). (Box 34)
    - Budget & Finances. (Box 34)
      See also Yelland.
    - CLA Bulletin. (Box 34)
    - Centennial Celebration Committee. (Box 34)
    - CLA Committees--Correspondence. (Box 34)
      See also Yelland and folders on specific committees, as CLA Regional Coop, etc.
    - CLA Ed. Committee. (Box 34)
    - Coman, Edwin T. (Box 34)
    - California Literary Centennial Celebration. (Box 34)
    - California Library History Committee. (Box 34)
    - California Youth Committee, February 24. (Box 34)
    - Clarke, Laurence J. (Box 34)
    - College & University Research Library Setion. (Box 34)
    - Constitutional Changes. (Box 34)
    - District Meetings. (Box 34)
    - District Presidents. (Box 34)
    - Dues Increase. (Box 34)
    - Executive Board Meetings. (Box 35, Folder E-S)
    - Exhibits at State Meeting. (Box 35)
    - Far Western Regional Meeting. (Box 35)
    - Golden Gate District. (Box 35)
    - Library Demonstration Bill. (Box 35)
    - Library Standards Committee. (Box 35)
    - Membership. (Box 35)
    - Membership Blanks. (Box 35)